<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on toxinu</title>
    <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on toxinu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toxi.nu/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to store your Python package metadata</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/how-to-store-your-python-package-metadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/how-to-store-your-python-package-metadata/</guid>
      <description>A small, but full of snippets, post about how to store your package metadata cleanly.
Let&amp;rsquo;s define a simple layout.
$ tree . . ├── my_package │ ├── __about__.py │ └── __init__.py └── setup.py 1 directory, 3 files  All your metadata lives in __about__.py like that:
__all__ = [ &amp;quot;__title__&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;__summary__&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;__uri__&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;__version__&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;__author__&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;__email__&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;__license__&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;__copyright__&amp;quot;, ] __title__ = &amp;quot;my-package&amp;quot; __summary__ = &amp;quot;My package is something.&amp;quot; __uri__ = &amp;quot;https://example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pip installable Django project</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/pip-installable-django-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/pip-installable-django-project/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll present you a Django layout which allow to ship your project (not app) as a Python package. Your users will be able to install it with pip for example.
This template is available as a Cookiecutter template. But I&amp;rsquo;ll remove every references, because this paper is mainly written to present you a Django project layout. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll do another post about Cookiecutter later.
My first need is to be able to install my Django project via pip install my-awesome-app and access it via my-awesome-app entry point without losing manage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H.P. Lovecraft, hallucinations et Tekeli&#39;li !</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/h.p.-lovecraft-hallucinations-et-tekelili-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/h.p.-lovecraft-hallucinations-et-tekelili-/</guid>
      <description>Premier article en français ! Il n&amp;rsquo;est jamais trop tard me direz-vous. Pourquoi ? Car je vais parler un peu de littérature et également d&amp;rsquo;un bouquin qui a été très tardivement mais récemment traduit en français.
L&amp;rsquo;ouvrage qui m&amp;rsquo;a donné envie de rédiger cet article est bien entendu, Les Montagnes Hallucinées du grand H.P. Lovecraft.
Je suppose que vous connaissez H.P. Lovecraft, grand écrivain dès son plus jeune âge, 9 ans (en 1899, il est donc né en 1890) jusqu&amp;rsquo;à ces 46 ans (mort jeune).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filtering and ordering with Restless</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/filtering-and-ordering-with-restless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/filtering-and-ordering-with-restless/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s continue with my previous blog post on Restless introduction with Django. Today I&amp;rsquo;ll show you two quick and simple Mixins for Restless. One for filtering and another for ordering.
I won&amp;rsquo;t show you how to create Django app, models, etc. This is not the subject.
Just to be clear, I have this models.py for our Pizza shop.
from django.db import models class Pizza(models.Model): name = models.CharField(max_length=100) price = models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restless for building Python RESTful API</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/restless-for-building-python-restful-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/restless-for-building-python-restful-api/</guid>
      <description>After trying to build RESTful API in Django with Django Rest Framework, my friend Pabluk allow me to discover Restless. A very small code base Python module to build RESTful API.
I&amp;rsquo;m totally not a huge fan of Django Rest Framework. It&amp;rsquo;s just to restricting if you don&amp;rsquo;t make a 100% REST API, and this is often the case. First of all, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a long progression period when you&amp;rsquo;ll have a bad use of this framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django SQL Debug - HTML reports of your HTTP requests</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/django-sql-debug---html-reports-of-your-http-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/django-sql-debug---html-reports-of-your-http-requests/</guid>
      <description>Django Debug Toolbar is an awesome tool but it has some limitations. It&amp;rsquo;s an HTML panel that is injected in your web pages that allow you to debug and profile your application at different layers. From HTTP to SQL requests.
But when you do applications with a REST pattern for example, with a full javascript client for example, it quickly become pain in the ass to debug your app. You can&amp;rsquo;t reproduce easily POST, PUT, etc&amp;hellip; requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye Disqus</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/goodbye-disqus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/goodbye-disqus/</guid>
      <description>Hi folks,
I just trash Disqus from my website cause of some disgusting issues.
 A bunch of js imported A bunch of ajax requests everywhere A big performance issue on page rendering, specially on mobile A urls migration wizard that just doesn&amp;rsquo;t work  I have tested Isso, a Python commentary mechanize. But still young and I fail to import all comments from Disqus. I make some try and thinking about Discourse integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animals can make music</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/animals-can-make-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/animals-can-make-music/</guid>
      <description>First of all, sorry about embedded videos.
I really don&amp;rsquo;t remember first time I listened the very first Animal Collective song. But I guess it was weird, maybe I just trashed it after some seconds. It don&amp;rsquo;t surprise me, like many complex music kind, you have to train your ears and your mind.
But in fact, I think this band deliver a very basic emotion. An emotion that just make you want to cry, move your head and just smile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traveling with Noisy drone</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/traveling-with-noisy-drone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/traveling-with-noisy-drone/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoy electro/drone/experimental music.
From Boards of Canada to Tim Hecker with Ben Frost, return to Fennesz and finish with Aphex Twin.
These guys are explorer, they try to take you away in their world. I want to write something because there are two recent albums that make sure that I love music exploration, Virgin from Tim Hecker and A U R O R A by Ben Frost.
For me exploration means that every part of the adventure won&amp;rsquo;t be enjoyable but it&amp;rsquo;s an experimentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two latest readings - *sick*</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/two-latest-readings---sick/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/two-latest-readings---sick/</guid>
      <description>Chuck Palahniuk is the guy that will use little daily weird things to make you very petty.
Rant I really enjoy this book.
It&amp;rsquo;s an oral biography about a strange boy (Buster Rant Casey) in a strange world (Middleton) where live strange residents. This story is timeless. You&amp;rsquo;ll retrieve subjects about sex, diseases, cars and cars. At the beginning, I feel a part of Fallout ambiance but after some chapters, not anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>« Monsieur le Président, une exécution se prépare… »</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/-monsieur-le-pr%C3%A9sident-une-ex%C3%A9cution-se-pr%C3%A9pare-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/-monsieur-le-pr%C3%A9sident-une-ex%C3%A9cution-se-pr%C3%A9pare-/</guid>
      <description>« Monsieur le Président, une exécution se prépare… »</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ephemeral Internet</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/ephemeral-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/ephemeral-internet/</guid>
      <description>I enjoy this ephemeral vision of the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bistouille and ASP 21&#34;</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/bistouille-and-asp-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/bistouille-and-asp-21/</guid>
      <description>I have admit that this is not a rage article.
Todo  Google go fuck yourself. AMQP is insta-boner like Atom Heart Mother You guys have to stop using Google services, pure shit everywhere. I&amp;rsquo;m a unicorn (need logout, dick) Thank you 4chan Faggotery TPB API WIP for culture sharing I&amp;rsquo;ll be back to Norway soon   Instead of simply recommending that you sodomize yourself with a retractable baton, let me recommend a specific model - the ASP 21&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No normal food for 2 months</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/no-normal-food-for-2-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/no-normal-food-for-2-months/</guid>
      <description>The game.
About four months ago I discover this blog entry and I realize that some other guys have been thinking about a new way to eat.
Full disclosure: I&amp;rsquo;m totally not a big eater, I was mainly eating pasta, rice, etc.. And sometimes sushi at restaurant, cause I love sushi.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always dreamed to be able to just swallow a pill every morning and to be in perfect food health in a very small kind of pollution to produce it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First thing to do after Ubuntu fresh install</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/first-thing-to-do-after-ubuntu-fresh-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/first-thing-to-do-after-ubuntu-fresh-install/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s time to return to sources, Linux, good buy Apple. But this is the first thing to do on every new Ubuntu installation.
sudo apt-get remove unity-lens-shopping sudo apt-get remove unity-scope-video-remote sudo apt-get remove unity-scope-musicstores sudo su - echo &amp;#39;OFFERS_URI=&amp;quot;https://localhost:0/&amp;quot;&amp;#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/environment  &amp;lsquo;Cause of spyware, you know&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Websocket with Flask and Gevent</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/websocket-with-flask-and-gevent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/websocket-with-flask-and-gevent/</guid>
      <description>Ubik, package manager for Unix If you follow me on Github you have maybe already seen that I currently develop a package manager for Unix, Ubik.
In order to test my API, I create a WebUI for Ubik and the websockets comes to me. My two prefered web framework are Django and Flask, but I need a lightweight web app, so welcome to Flask.
Node.js, blah, blah Ok, I have many many times hear good things about Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Pages to Heroku</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/github-pages-to-heroku/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/github-pages-to-heroku/</guid>
      <description>Synopsis My initial goal was to put my jekyll website on Heroku but I have encountered many problems due of my bad Ruby level and pygment usage.
During month my jekyll website was freely hosted by GitHub Pages. Thanks for all the fish. But GitHub is not for app hosting.
Many hours of:
 &amp;ldquo;What the fuck I have 404 ?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Oh Damn it my local Jekyll render it correctly and not on Github&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Ohh enough, it was just the yaml header with quotes which give me fucking 404&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TheMall - A simple Python web shopping list</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/themall---a-simple-python-web-shopping-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/themall---a-simple-python-web-shopping-list/</guid>
      <description>I have used myTinyTodo for at least 1 year but I&amp;rsquo;m fed up of Mysql database and Php&amp;hellip; Am I serious ?
 &amp;ldquo;Mysql database for shopping list ? A bazooka to kill a fly ?&amp;rdquo;
 The plan is to create a simple Python todo list mainly for shopping list with mobile interface. It&amp;rsquo;s was the objectif.
Tools box:
 Python Flask Twitter bootstrap Json  Description
 Simple authentification Very light design Mobile design (responsive) Very very light Todo List In fact, looks like a Shopping List  You can see project page here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Server LTS upgrades are stress test</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/ubuntu-server-lts-upgrades-are-stress-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/ubuntu-server-lts-upgrades-are-stress-test/</guid>
      <description>Update  Sept, 24 2012  This article is now deprecated, Ubuntu now have a clean upgrade script. Just use do-release-upgrade.
 This week I had to upgrade some Ubuntu Server 10.04 to the new Canonical present. And as much to upgrade my Debian scares me, then Ubuntu is a fabulous stress test&amp;hellip;
I admit to not being an Ubuntu expert ( Debian too ) but the do-release-upgrade is like :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nagios Oracle health plugin</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/nagios-oracle-health-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/nagios-oracle-health-plugin/</guid>
      <description>This is more a memo than an article. A quick and dirty check_oracle_health plugin installation, with prerequires.
Developped by Gerhard Lausser, an active Shinken developper with Jean Gabès.
Like most of Nagios plugins, it&amp;rsquo;s in Perl language and it&amp;rsquo;s use DBD::Oracle module, and this module need an Oracle client.
Oracle Instant Client You have to create a fucking Oracle account&amp;hellip; Yes I know you think :
&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s this great article ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jekyll with Git and Hooks</title>
      <link>https://toxi.nu/blog/jekyll-with-git-and-hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toxi.nu/blog/jekyll-with-git-and-hooks/</guid>
      <description>Good bye my lovely Pyame&amp;hellip; Hello Jekyll ! Pyame is my personnal static website creator written in Python under heavy development. These days I searched powerfull, light and easy to use static website creator, and Jekyll is arrived. Thanks God.
In short, these programs parse differents files written in a special syntax, for example : Markdown, Textile, etc. An easy syntax to make your articles or docs more swag. And it generate html output.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>